Guide to the Hillary Chute Collection of Catwoman 1972-1994
University of Chicago Library
Chute, Hillary. Collection of Catwoman
1972-1994
2 linear feet (2 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Hillary Chute Collection contains 27 comics from 1972-1994, including four issues of Marvel’s The Cat (1972-3), 20 issues of DC’s Catwoman from 1989-1994, and one issue each of Green Arrow (DC, 1994), Felicia Hardy: The Black Cat (Marvel, 1994) and Wizard Magazine (1994). Collected by Hillary L. Chute, professor of American literature and art.
Information on Use
Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Hillary L. Chute (b. 1976) is a professor of American literature and visual art, known for her work on graphic novels. She was associate professor of English and the Department of Visual Arts at the University of Chicago from 2010-2015. Chute earned her Ph.D. in English from Rutgers University in 2006. She is the author of several books including Why Comics? From Underground to Everywhere (HarperCollins, 2017), Disaster Drawn: Visual Witness, Comics, and Documentary Form (Harvard University Press, 2016), Outside the Box: Interviews with Contemporary Cartoonists (University of Chicago Press, 2014), and Graphic Women: Life Narrative and Contemporary Comics (Columbia University Press, 2010).
Scope Note
The Hillary Chute Collection contains 27 comics from 1972-1994, including four issues of The Cat (Marvel, 1972-3), 20 issues of Catwoman (DC, 1989-1994), and one issue each of Green Arrow (DC, 1994), Felicia Hardy: The Black Cat (Marvel, 1994) and Wizard Magazine (1994), a monthly magazine about comic books which ran from 1991-2011.
The four The Cat comics in this collection are the only comics featuring the Cat. Catwoman: Her Sister’s Keeper (Folder 9, the collection of issues 1-4 in folders 5-8) was the first solo mini-series for Catwoman, who had previously appeared in Batman comics. The ten sequential issues of Catwoman in Box 2 (Folders 3-13) are significant as they make up the beginning of Catwoman’s first ongoing solo series. The issue of Felicia Hardy: The Black Cat (Marvel, 1994, folder 16) is one of four in this character’s first solo limited series; her first ongoing solo series began in 2019.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
Browse finding aids by topic.
Dopierala, Walter C. Comic Book Collection
Scotch, Hank. Moby Dick Comic Books. Collection
Clowes, Daniel. Archive
Subject Headings
Catwoman (Fictitious character)--Comic books, strips, etc.; Catwoman (Fictitious character); DC Comics, Inc.; Marvel Comics Group; Women heroes in mass media; Women heroes in literature; Cartooning; Comic books, strips, etc.; Graphic novels; Comics (Graphic works)
INVENTORY
- The Cat, #1, November 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Cat, #2, January 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Cat, #3, April 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Cat, #4, June 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Catwoman, #1 of 4, February 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Catwoman, #2 of 4, March 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Catwoman, #3 of 4, April 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Catwoman, #4 of 4, May 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Catwoman: Her Sister’s Keeper, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Catwoman: Defiant, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Catwoman: Showcase ’93, #3, March 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Catwoman: Showcase ’93, #4, April 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Catwoman, #1, August 1993, c. 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Catwoman, #1, August 1993, c. 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Catwoman, #2, September 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Catwoman, #3, October 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Catwoman, #4, November 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Catwoman, #5, December 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Catwoman, #6, January 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Catwoman, #7, February 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Catwoman, #8, March 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Catwoman, #9, April 1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Catwoman, #10, May 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Catwoman Annual, #1, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Green Arrow, #86, May 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Felicia Hardy: The Black Cat, #2, August 1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Wizard, #33, May 1994 [Note: This piece may not be removed from its original packaging.] (Box 2, Folder 17)